Santa Clara, CA 95054 cesarkylecasil@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ckcasil github.com/ccasil cesarkylecasil.me

#### **Summary**

I am a Computer Science major practicing full stack development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) I have experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. My primary goal is to contribute my passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on my technical skills.

### Education

#### University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks.
 Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

Technical Skills <u>L</u>anguages: **JavaScript** (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, **Python**, C, LATEX <u>Front-End</u>: **HTML**, **CSS**, **jQuery**, AJAX, **Bootstrap**, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response

 $\underline{\mathbf{D}}$ atabase: SQL ( $\mathbf{MySQL}$ , SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js,

Django ORM, Core Data,  $\mathbf{CRUD}$  operations

<u>Frameworks and Libraries:</u> **Angular**, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask <u>Development Tools:</u> **Git**, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

(EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Miscellaneous: Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures, Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Ar-

chitecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model

View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

#### Experience

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Jan 2018–Present

- Building Full-Stack, modern, responsive web applications for clients while providing quick feedback and support
- Managed a small team to work with clients to create websites for various needs

#### MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

## Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Translated UI mockups into a working, interactive Android application using Android Studio and Java during its early stages
- $\bullet$  Designed and created a functional implementation of the mobile applications interface
- Testing and quality assurance

## Projects

# Megumi Hiramoto

Sept 2018–Ongoing

Portfolio for Academy of Art student to display her studies in Fashion Journalism.

• **Technologies Used:** React, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Wed Design (RWD)

# Love Changing the World, INC.

Jun 2018–Oct 2018

Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding.

• Technologies Used: React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3,

JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API

Gym Log

Apr 2018

Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Dojo Attendance Tracker

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

## Baskin Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.

• Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)